Guide to the Gerald Robert Vizenor Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- June 2008 Acquisition, circa 1976-2008; 11.6; (16 boxes) + 1 object
  - Writings, circa 1976-2008
    - Edward Curtis: Pictorialist and Ethnographic Adventurist, circa 2000 (Box 69)
    - Essays, circa 1999-2000 (Box 69)
      Includes photocopies of various essays, including "Wounded Knee: December 1890: The End of the Century," "Gerald Vizenor and A. Robert Lee in Conversation," "The Elevator Shaman," "Fusions of Survivance: Haiku Scenes and Native Dream Songs."
    - "Father Meme"/"Panic Portage," drafts, publisher's proofs, and related correspondence, circa 2007; 4 (Box 69)
    - "Father Meme" / "Panic Portage", circa 2007-2008; 4 (Box 70)
    - Geneva/Vienna Lecture: "Native American Narratives: Resistance and Survivance", circa 2006 (Box 70)
      Includes draft of keynote speech given at the Vienna Conference on November 17, 2006.
    - Notebook: "Genocide", circa 2006 (Box 70)
      Includes one holograph notebook regarding a graduate seminar on genocide, given at the University of New Mexico, in the Fall of 2006.
    - Genocide Tribunals: Human Rights and Native Survivance, essay drafts, research materials, and related correspondence, circa 2005-2006; 5 (Box 70)
    - George Morrison: Anishinaabe Expressionist Artist, 2004-2006; 2 (Box 70)
      Includes numerous essay drafts with revisions and related correspondence, and three sheets of color slides of Morrison's work.
    - Griever: An American Monkey King in China, bound page proofs of the reprint edition, circa 1990 (Box 70)
    - Literary Chance: Essays on Native American Survivance, early drafts with corrections and additions, circa 2007; 2 (Box 70)
    - Native American Narratives: Resistance and Survivance, circa 2005 (Box 70)
      Includes a draft of Vizenor's chapter with corrections, dated February 24, 2005, as well as related correspondence.
    - Native Liberty: Natural Reason and Cultural Survivance: Selected Essays, circa 2007-2008; 6 (Box 70)
      Includes a first draft with notes and corrections, a manuscript copy dated 2008, and a final copy dated July 23, 2007.
    - Native American Literature, circa 2004 (Box 71)
      Includes three variant drafts of an essay written for a Native American Literature catalog for bookseller Ken Lopez, dated August 2004, with related correspondence and a copy of the catalog.
    - Native Provenance and Museum Collections, circa 2006-2007; 4 (Box 71)
      Includes drafts, correspondence, and research for a lecture and panel discussion given at the National Museum of the American Indian.
    - Native Survivance and Irony, circa 2006 (Box 71)
      Includes drafts with corrections, correspondence, and research for a lecture given at the Bavarian American Studies Association in Munich, Germany, on May 19, 2006.
    - New Mexico Lecture: "Survivance Narratives", circa 2008 (Box 71)
      Includes a draft, corrections, and correspondence for a keynote lecture given at the Indigenous Research Conference at the University of New Mexico, on April 3, 2008.
    - Poetry, circa 1980 (Box 71)
      Includes manuscripts of poems through 1980 with corrections and revisions.
    - Poetry 2004, circa 2003-2005 (Box 71)
      Includes stray poem drafts with corrections.
    - Postindian Reflections: Gerald Vizenor and A. Robert Lee in Conversation, circa 2008 (Box 71)
      Includes multiple drafts with corrections, plus related correspondence.
    - The Progress and White Earth Survivance, circa 2006 (Box 71)
      Includes two variant drafts and research dated April, 2006.
    - Red River Conference, circa 2005 April (Box 71)
      Includes correspondence and notes concerning the Red River Conference on World Literature, held at North Dakota State University, Fargo, ND.
    - Survivance: Narratives of Native Presence, circa 2006-2008; 4 (Box 71)
      Includes drafts with corrections, as well as general business correspondence and correspondence between essay contributors and the publisher.
    - Syllabi, circa 1976-1992; 4 (Box 71)
      Includes syllabi for courses in Native American Studies at the University of California, Berkeley, and elsewhere.
    - We Are at Home, circa 2006 (Box 71)
      Includes variant drafts with corrections, plus correspondence, for Vizenor's foreword to "We Are at Home," by Shannon Pennefeather.
    - Western Literature Association Award Lecture, circa 2005 (Box 71)
      Includes two variant drafts with corrections, as well as a conference program.
    - Reviews, Hiroshima Bugi, circa 2003-2004 (Box 71)
    - Research materials, circa 2004-2007
      - Dennis Banks -- Ojibwa Warrior, circa 2005 (Box 71)
        Contains general research materials and legal records concerning Dennis Banks, as well as Vizenor's notes and correspondence.
      - Father Meme, circa 2004-2007; 3 (Box 72)
        Includes a notebook of research materials on Catholic Church abuses of Native American children, as well as other research for "Father Meme."
      - Red Lake, circa 2005 March (Box 72)
        Contains research, newspaper clippings, and correspondence concerning the Red Lake Reservation school shootings in March, 2005.
      - Ward Churchill, circa 2005; 2 (Box 72)
        Folders contain research and correspondence regarding the controversy surrounding the University of Colorado professor Ward Churchill.
  - Writings by Others, circa 2004-2006
    - Carson, Ben. "The 'Cosmopolitan Consciousness' of Gerald Vizenor and Native American Literary Separatism", circa 2006 (Box 72)
    - The Columbia History of American Indian Literatures of the United States, 1945 - Present (Box 72)
      Contains Chapter Three ("Cannons and Canonization," by Kimberly M. Blaeser) and Chapter Five ("Non-Fiction Writers," by David Murray). Edited by Eric Cheyfitz.
    - Cox, James H. "Muting White Noise", circa 2004; 2 (Box 72)
    - Dennis, Helen M. "A Crack in the Universe: Towards a Spatialized Poetics of Native American Literature," proposal, circa 2005 (Box 72)
    - Garrait-Bourrier, Anne. "N. Scott Momaday, The Bear Man", circa 2006 (Box 72)
    - Helstern, Linda. "The Fractal Geometry of Bearheart: The Heirship Chronicles" (Box 72)
    - Huddleston, Jason T. "The Dialectic of Self: An Existential Reading of Identity in Selected Contemporary American Indian Literatures", circa 2004 (Box 72)
    - Kilpatrick, Alan. "The Wolf Stalker", circa 2005 (Box 72)
      Contains a partial manuscript, written under the pseudonym A.E. Blackwood, with a cover letter.
    - Lockard, Joe. "Facing the Windigoo: Gerald Vizenor and Primo Levi", circa 2006 (Box 72)
    - Pettigrew, Dawn Karima. "The Marriage of Saints", circa 2004-2005 (Box 72)
    - Pierotti, Raymond. "Sits Beside Him", circa 2005 (Box 72)
    - Schlesier, Sibylle. "Bill Red Hat: Cheyenne Storier", circa 2005 (Box 72)
      Contains manuscripts of Schlesier's introduction and epilogue, plus correspondence.
    - Taylor, Paul. "Introduction", circa 2005 (Box 72)
      Contains a manuscript of Taylor's introduction (to "Native American Literatures") on Bearheart, with Vizenor's suggestions, comments, and correspondence.
    - Trickster of Liberty, circa 2005 (Box 72)
      Contains correspondence and cover proof for "Trickster of Liberty," as well as the foreword to "Bear Island" by Jace Weaver.
    - Weber, Ivan. "Coherent Incoherence: The Literature of Gerald Vizenor", circa 2005 (Box 72)
  - Academic and Conference Materials, circa 1991-2008
    - Final Exams - Berkeley, circa 1991-1994 (Box 73)
    - Letters of Recommendation, circa 1992-2006 (Box 73)
    - Final Grades - Berkeley, circa 2001-2005 (Box 73)
    - Japan, circa 2004; 3 (Box 73)
      Includes correspondence, information, and itineraries concerning an Osaka University position; student papers from a seminar on Hiroshima, human rights, and genocide; and various manuscripts and lecture notes from Vizenor's series of Japan lectures from October, 2004.
      Disk #20080530-16443.0002; "Keio University Tokyo Lecture Oct 25, 2004 Photographs"
    - American Studies New Mexico, circa 2004-2005 (Box 73)
      Includes syllabi, correspondence, and materials concerning Vizenor's American Studies courses at the University of New Mexico.
    - Miscellaneous Academic and Conference Materials, circa 2006-2007; 8 (Box 73)
      Includes miscellaneous materials such as travel documents, brochures, and correspondence regarding various literary conferences, lectures, and trips. The contents include materials on the Monterey Institute (2007), the "American Aesthetics" conference (Geneva, 2006), the "Native American and First Nations" conference (Vienna, 2006), the Modern Library Association (Philadelphia, 2006), the University of Minnesota "Genocide Tribunals" (2006), Paris trips (2006-2007), the "Montpellier Symposium" (2007), and University of Minnesota tenure materials.
      Disk #20080530-16443.0003; "LSC WLSC Orientation"
    - White Earth Reservation Constitutional Conference, circa 2007; 2 (Box 73)
      Includes business and organizational materials from the White Earth Reservation Constitutional Conference, October 19-20, 2007, plus correspondence and notes.
    - University of New Mexico Press, circa 2008 (Box 73)
      Includes Univeristy of New Mexico Press Committee meeting memos and minutes.
  - Other Papers
    - Publications, 2004-2008; 2 (Box 73)
      Includes 4 computer disks
      Includes miscellaneous publications: UNM Today, Fuse Magazine, European Review of Native American Studies, Anishinaabeg Today, PMLA, Ojibwe News, Minnesota History, Fiction Collective, etc.
      Disk #20080530-16443.0004; DVD, "American Genocide and Justice"
      Disk #20080530-16443.0005; CD-R, "11-14-06 Seminar"
      Disks #20080530-16443.0006, #20080530-16443.0007; CD (commercially mastered), "The Native American Journey"
    - Travel Documents, circa 2006
      - Montpellier Conference, circa 2006 (Box 73)
        Contains papers, travel documents, and correspondence concerning the "Gerald Vizenor, Litterateur at Large" International Symposium, held at Universite Paul Valery in Montpellier, France, in May of 2006.
      - Montpellier Conference, circa 2006 (Box 74)
      - Munich May 19, 2006, circa 2006 (Box 74)
      - London, Paris, July 13-24, 2006, circa 2006 (Box 74)
    - Legal Records, circa 1996-2005
      - Highlands Club, circa 1996-2001 (Box 74)
        Includes documents relating to the case of "Gerald Vizenor v. Robin Mickle" regarding Highland Country Club (of Oakland, CA) fees.
      - 742 Camino Francisca Complaint Umphrey, circa 2004-2005 (Box 74)
        Includes documents relating to the case of "Gerald Vizenor v. Michael Umphrey" regarding a Santa Fe home.
    - Personal Effects, circa 2003, 2006-2007; 3 (Box 74)
      Includes a Patrick Henry Class of '53 50th Class Reunion brochure (2003), one year planner (2003), a reproduction of Pavel Cerenkov's I.D. from the National Atomic Museum, three name tags (2006), two pocket diaries (2006-2007), one international driving permit (2007), and business papers regarding a 2007 house purchase.
    - Miscellaneous, 2000-2007; 3 (Box 74)
    - Robert Lee's lecture on Gerald Vizenor, given at the Universite Paul Valery in Montpellier, France, 2006 May; YCALMSS539_0003; 1; 00:34:47 (Box 102, Item barcode 39002102339372)
    - Broadside: Those Stubborn Flies, 1993 October 3 (Box 74)
      Consists of one framed haiku broadside published by Woodland Pattern bookstore, Milwaukee.
    - Distinguished Minnesotan Award, circa 2005 (Box 74)
    - American Book Award, 1988 (Box 74)
    - Book by Miyuki Aozama (on Native American Literature and a holograph cover letter dated June 6, 2004) (Box 74)
    - Bemidji State University Honorary Alumnus Award, 2005 (Box 75 Oversize)
    - Bemidji State University Distinguished Minnesotan Award, 2005 (Box 75 Oversize)
    - Western Literature Association's Distinguished Achievement Award, 2005 (Box 75 Oversize)
    - Posters and Original Art (Box 76 Oversize)
      Includes a "Black Arrow" movie poster (circa 1944), a "My Chippewa" sheet music (circa 1907), a "Sacred Trusts" drawings, and a watercolor painting.
    - Vizenor Posters, circa 2004-2005 (Box 76 Oversize)
    - Posters and Original Art (Box 77 Oversize)
      Includes a "Kalispell I" print, a Jaune Quick-to-See Smith poster, and a "Wordarrows Autographing Party with Gerald Vizenor" poster.
    - Original cover art for "Shadow Distance", by Dirk Görtler (Box 77 Oversize)
    - Photographs, posters and poetry broadsides, 2 (Box 77 Oversize)
    - Harold of Orange posters, circa 1984 (Box 78 Oversize)
    - "Earthdivers in Higher Ed (The Chair of Tears) - Drinking for Blood Quamtum - part 1", circa 1983 (Box 78 Oversize)
      Ink brushwork on paper by Jaune Quick-to-See Smith.
    - "Bloodline Tribal Survivors (Sand Creek Survivors) pg. 72 - part 2", circa 1983 (Box 78 Oversize)
    - "Metis Tricksters and Shamans (Mouse Proof Martin) pg. 119, 120, 121 - part 3", circa 1983 (Box 78 Oversize)
    - "Earthdivers at the Indian Center (The Sociodowser) pg. 201 - part 4", circa 1983 (Box 78 Oversize)
    - "Metis Tricksters and Shamans (Rubio Blue Welcome) pg. 152, 153 - part 5", circa 1983 (Box 78 Oversize)
  - Object
    - Typewriter (Box 79)
      Gerald Vizenor's Smith Corona manual typewriter in a case with a cloth flag/map of Sicily laid within.
- October 2012 Acquisition, 1987-2012; 3; (4 boxes)
  Purchased from Ken Lopez Bookseller on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2012.
  This acquisition consists of correspondence, writings, personal papers, photographs, printed material, compacts discs, and other papers by or relating to Gerald Vizenor.
  - Writings, business papers, and correspondence, 1987- 2012 (Box 81)
    Tanzania reading notes and notebooks, royalty statements, business and academic correspondence, tearsheets and reviews.
  - Writings and business papers, circa 2000s-2010s (Box 82)
    Legal papers, business and academic correspondence. Writings include White Earth Nation, Blue Ravens and others.
  - Literature prize broadsides, book proof with artwork and other materials., circa 1988-2011 (Box 83)
    Artwork for Le Dernier des Mohicans by A. Pierre.
  - Writings, 2012 (Box 84)
    "Blue Ravens"
  - Electronic media, circa 2000s-2010s (Box 85)
- September 2015 Acquisition, 1974-2015; 9.92; (14 boxes) + 2 broadside
  Purchased from Ken Lopez Bookseller on the Walter McClintock Memorial Fund, 2015.
  This acquisition consists of correspondence, writings, printed material, electronic files, and other papers by or relating to Gerald Vizenor.
  Arranged roughly in the order in which the papers were received.
  - Empire Treasons, 2014- (Box 86)
  - Favor of Crows, circa 2015 (Box 86)
  - White Earth Reservation Tribal Council, Letters to Kevin Washburn, 2013 July 26 (Box 86)
  - London travel details, 2014- (Box 86)
  - Birgit Dawes: New Directions in North American Studies, 2014- (Box 86)
    Contains materials concerning international conference celebrating Gerald Vizenor.
  - Vienna travel details, 2014- (Box 86)
  - Native American Writing Series, promotional material, Spring 2015 (Box 86)
  - Paris book reading, 2014- (Box 86)
  - Gerald Vizenor's Trickster Hermeneutics, by Kirstin L. Squint, circa 2012 (Box 86)
  - Japan travel details, 2014- (Box 86)
  - Transpacific Fakelore of the Asiatic: Relocating Ethnicity in Nikkei Literature and Native North American Literature, 2013- (Box 86)
    Doctoral dissertation by Yukari Kato
  - Favor of Crows and Blue Ravens, promotional material, 2014- (Box 86)
  - Favor of Crows, 2013 September 26 (Box 86)
    Includes correspondence to Ann Brash about changes to manuscript.
  - Western Literature talk at Berkeley, 2013 October 09 (Box 86)
  - The Aesthetics of Survivance: Literary Theory and Practice, circa 2008 (Box 86)
  - Santa Fe Seminar, 2013- (Box 86)
  - Lecture material, 2014- (Box 86)
    Includes "Literary Transmotions: Native Cosmototemic Art" and a University of New Mexico and UC Berkely name tag.
  - National Museum of the American Indian, 2014- (Box 86)
  - Empire Treasons, 2014- (Box 86)
  - Global Associations, 2014- (Box 86)
    Includes additional notes, partial drafts, and email correspondence.
  - Blue Ravens, 2013- (Box 86)
    Includes book jacket and correspondence.
  - Blue Ravens, corresponsdence, 2013-2014 (Box 86)
  - Haiku Poems, correspondence, 2013-2014 (Box 86)
  - North Dakota State University, travel details and correspondence, 2014- (Box 86)
  - Minneapolis travel details and correspondence, 2014- (Box 86)
  - Empire Treasons and Literary Transmotion, lecture material, 2014- (Box 86)
  - Literary Transmotion, 2013-2014 (Box 86)
    Includes heavily annotated copy of Literary Transmotion.
  - Anishinaabeg Today, 2014 April 09 (Box 86)
  - Yakuri Kato's Dissertation Evaluation, 2014- (Box 86)
  - Fakelore Ethnicity: Ranald MacDonald and His Literary Followers, Yukari Kato, circa 2013 (Box 86)
  - April Anson correspondence, 2014- (Box 86)
    Includes a seminar paper by April Anson
  - New York Museum, travel details, correspondence, and brochures, 2014- (Box 86)
  - Texas Institute for Literary & Textual Studies, promotional material, 2014- (Box 86)
  - 48th Annual Western Literature Association Conference, program schedule, 2013- (Box 86)
  - Correspondence to Gerald Vizenor, 2007 September 22 (Box 86)
    Unidentified correspondence to Vizenor from "Joe"
  - Minneapolis Star Saturday Magazine, 1978 July 29 (Box 87)
  - Email correspondence, 2013-2014; 8 folders (Box 88)
  - Lecture material, circa 2000 (Box 88)
    Includes "Native Transmotion," "Literary Animals," "Fugitive Poses," and "Wistful Envies".
  - Essays on literary theory and ideologies, circa 1984 (Box 88)
  - Notes, talks, and writings on water use in the West, circa 2002 (Box 88)
  - American Studies 102: Native American Philosophies, circa 1997 (Box 88)
  - Lecture notes, 1980-1990 (Box 88)
  - Native American Studies, Atomic Bomb: Los Alamos to Hiroshima, 1993-2012; 4 folders (Box 88)
    Including American Studies course materials.
  - George Morrison's "Turning the Feather Around", circa 1998 (Box 88)
  - White Earth: Images of Survivance, 2012-; 2 folders (Box 89)
  - Expedition- The Magazine of the UPENN Museum of Archaeology and Anthropology, Winter 2013 (Box 89)
  - White Earth Constitution: Ratification of a Native Democratic Constitution, 2014- (Box 89)
  - Anishinaabeg Today, featuring Erma Vizenor, 2013 October 11 (Box 89)
  - Chair of Tears review, 2012 March 19 (Box 89)
  - Le Journal des Poetes, Belgium, 2013- (Box 89)
  - Father Meme review, 2008 October 16 (Box 89)
  - Correspondence between Erma Vizenor and John Ratzloff, 2014- (Box 89)
  - Gerald Vizenor's correspondence to Gary Strankman, 2013 January 04 (Box 89)
  - Texas Institute for Literature & Textual Studies, promotional material, 2014- (Box 89)
  - Ojibwe News, notes, 2013- (Box 89)
  - White Earth Symposium A, October 2013 (Box 89)
    Includes Gerald Vizenor's correspondence to Erma Vizenor and others.
  - White Earth Constitution, Start Tribune article, 2013 November 21 (Box 89)
  - Wesleyan University book catalog, Spring 2014 (Box 89)
    Includes Wesleyan University Press's summary and advertisement for Gerald Vizenor's Blue Ravens and Favor of Crows.
  - University Press of New England, Spring 2014 (Box 89)
  - Anishinaabeg Today, 2013 December 04 (Box 89)
  - Western Literature Association Conference, Berkeley, 2013-; 2 folders (Box 89)
  - Chair of Tears proof cover, 2012- (Box 89)
  - Constitutional Reform Workbook, 2013- (Box 89)
  - Anishinaabeg Today, 2013-; 2 folders (Box 89)
  - Constitutional Reform booklet, 2013- (Box 89)
  - Texas lecture material, 2013- (Box 89)
  - White Earth symposium, 2013- (Box 89)
  - Blue Ravens, final corrections, 2014- (Box 89)
  - Blue Ravens, bound typescript, 2014- (Box 89)
  - Empire Treasons: White Earth and the Great War, 2014- (Box 89)
  - London and Vienna lectures, 2014- (Box 89)
  - Japan lectures, 2014- (Box 89)
  - Summer Institute materials, Summer 2013 (Box 89)
  - University of Texas, Austin lectures, 2013- (Box 89)
  - Favor of Crows, introduction with annotations, circa 2013 (Box 89)
  - Globalizing the Word: Transnationalism and Native American Literature, list of speakers, 2013- (Box 89)
  - Literary Eats, promotional material, 2013- (Box 89)
  - American Studies AMST 519 teacher evaluation forms, Fall 2012 (Box 89)
  - Blue Ravens, uncorrected page proofs, 2014-; 2 folders (Box 89)
  - Favor of Crows, page proofs, 2013- (Box 89)
  - Anishinaabeg Today, 2013-; 3 folders (Box 89)
  - Constitutional Reform Workbook, 2013- (Box 89)
  - Star Tribune articles, 2013- (Box 89)
  - The Arrogance of Tribal Power, 1988-2009 (Box 89)
    Including an email correspondence from Roxanne Jensen to Gerald Vizenor.
  - Post-Indian Warriors, undated (Box 101)
  - Email correspondence, 2013-; 4 folders (Box 90)
  - David Bradley's Honor event invitation, 2013- (Box 90)
    Includes information about ALS, a note from Robert (?) to Gerald Vizenor and wife, and a "What Would Tricksters Do" wrist band.
  - Favor of Crows, proof, 2013- (Box 90)
  - Water Striders, 1997 October (Box 90)
  - Favor of Crows, circa 2013 (Box 90)
  - Blue Ravens, circa 2014; 2 folders (Box 90)
  - Weber: The Contemporary West, Spring - Summer 2013 (Box 90)
    Includes email correspondence to Michael Wutz and Billy Stratton.
  - The White Earth Nation: Ratification of a Native Democratic Constitution, 2011- (Box 90)
  - Bearheart, preview, 2009 May 28 (Box 90)
  - Ice Trickster, notes, 2013- (Box 90)
  - Favor of Crows, circa 2013 (Box 90)
  - Anishinaabeg Today, 2013 May 01 (Box 90)
  - Haiku Scenes, introduction, 2013- (Box 90)
  - Mediating Indianness, poems and discussions, 2013- (Box 90)
  - Anishinaabeg Today, 2013 June 13 (Box 90)
  - Native American Writing brochure, 2011- (Box 90)
  - White Earth Nation, State of the Nation report, 2012- (Box 90)
  - State of the Nation address, handbill and schedule, 2013- (Box 90)
  - Globalizing the Word, promotional material, 2013- (Box 90)
  - Weber controversy, hard copy and email correspondence, 2012-2013 (Box 90)
  - The Uptowner - Gerald Vizenor and Laura Hall, 2012- (Box 90)
  - Tracking the Trickster Home, Autumn 2006 (Box 90)
    Master's thesis by Stephen Hawley
  - White Earth Nation promotional material, 2013- (Box 90)
  - Sakahan exhibition, Ottawa, 2013- (Box 90)
  - Blue Ravens promotional material, France, 2013- (Box 90)
  - The Cosmopolitan Consciousness, by Ben Carson, 2006 (Box 90)
  - Seminar book lists, schedules, correspondence, etc., 2009-2011 (Box 90)
  - Photograph of Gerald Vizenor and Laura Hall at Season 52, circa 2014 (Box 90)
  - Anishinaabeg Today, 2013 June 05 (Box 91)
  - Globalizing the Word Conference correspondence, 2012-2013 (Box 91)
  - Native Literature: Independent Study, Spring 2013 (Box 91)
  - Anishinaabeg Today, 2012-2013; 3 folders (Box 91)
  - Minnesota Historical Society trustee directory, 2013- (Box 91)
  - Chancers, promotional postcards, circa 2001 (Box 91)
  - Handmade book of haiku poems for Gerald Vizenor, by Kristi Bjorklund, 1978-1980 (Box 91)
  - Handmade book of handwritten poems for Gerald Vizenor, 1977- (Box 91)
    Unidentified author
  - Email correspondence, 2011-2013 (Box 91)
  - White Earth media, undated (Box 101)
  - Blue Ravens, notes, 2011-2012 (Box 92)
  - Blue Ravens, circa 2012 (Box 92)
  - Blue Ravens, copy-edited manuscript, 2013-; 2 folders (Box 92)
  - Artists reference material, circa 2011 (Box 92)
  - Blue Ravens reference materials, circa 2011 (Box 92)
    Includes records of Indian participants in the 1st World War
  - Research material on Japonisme, circa 2011 (Box 92)
  - Research material, WWI American forestry, 2011- (Box 92)
  - Research material WWI thesis, "The American Indian in the Great War", circa 2011 (Box 92)